This is it, Rupert.
Our big chance.
Maybe next week, your
name will go up in lights.
Rupert, the talk of the town.
You won't let me
down, will you, Rupert?
You'll do everything
just like I taught you?
Ah yes, now...
Now, how about a
dress rehearsal? Here.
The curtain is up.
You're on the stage.
Stay right there
when I tell you.
Now get ready for
our song and dance.
Are you all set?
One, two...
Now we've got to do
the dance in unison.
And it's got to be perfect, for
everything depends on how we do it.
You all set? Here we go.
- Phil, I'm so glad to see you.
- Joe, how have you been?
Not too good, but
everything's gonna change now.
Sit down. How are you, miss?
This is Joe Mahoney. He used
to work out of my father's office.
And the best lion-tamer in
the business. Weren't you?
- Go on with you.
- Delighted, I'm sure.
Thank you.
What's this new act
that you wired me about?
Here it is. Now greet
the man, Rupert.
You mean, that's it?
That's it.
- A squirrel?
- Sure.
- You wouldn't fool me, would you?
- He's a great performer.
Something like Rupert only
happens once in a million years.
I'm sorry, Joe, but
I'm not interested.
- He's not box office.
- Come on, honey, we're late.
- Phil, you haven't seen what he can do.
- I've seen enough already.
Joe, look...
a lion is a big, savage beast.
He's vicious, ruthless.
A bloodthirsty killer from the
faraway jungles of darkest Africa.
So he's box office.
But a little pipsqueak
thing like a squirrel...
that anybody can see
anyplace, in any park, anytime...
Besides, he's so small, they'd
never see him in the balcony.
But I tell you,
Rupert's almost human.
- Come on, honey, we're late.
- Just a minute.
Look, Joe...
I'd love to give you a break. I
know things have been tough.
- But he just ain't...
- Box office.
Goodbye, Mr. Dingle. I'll pay
you every cent that I owe you.
You should, Mahoney.
Pete. Get a broom and pail,
and help me clean this place out.
It's nice and peaceful here,
ain't it? You can breathe.
Take a good look around
at some of your new pals.
I want you to go on and get
acquainted with them. Come on.
That's it.
Don't be stubborn
about this. Go on.
To be sure, it's a silly outfit.
There you are. They
would have laughed at you.
Now, go on. Yes, I
know you don't want to.
I know you'll be happy here.
I know they'll love you.
You'll be the life of the party...
doing the somersaults and all
the cute little tricks that I taught you.
Go on, I tell you.
Beat it, I tell you.
What shall I do?
You just ain't box office.
Papa, do you think we might have
some money in that Chicago account?
I heard from that bank last week.
I think I got the letter with me.
Here it is.
It says, "Dear Mr. Amendola, this is the
last monthly statement we will mail you.
"We feel it is hardly worth three
cents to tell you you have two cents."
Let's get going.
Look at all those lucky people,
hurrying home with arms full of packages.
They'll have turkey for
Christmas, packages under the tree.
Don't envy them, Rosalinda.
I bet every one of them faced a
Christmas like us at some time or another.
Besides, it ain't Christmas yet. Saint
Nick may have a bundle for us, too.
But the trouble is, we ain't got
no address he can deliver them to.
Amendola! The Amendola Trio!
- Joe Mahoney!
- Joe, darling!
Now, don't tell me
this is little Rosie.
She's certainly growing
fast. A little too fast.
It seems like only yesterday
I bought her them shoes...
and already she's
complaining they're too small.
And with you? How's
the act been going?
Us? Great. Sensational.
If I made any more money,
I'd have to buy myself a wallet.
And you know something?
We've played the circuit so
many times, just for a change...
we booked a European tour.
- Europe?
- London, Paris, Budapest.
And in India, we gave a performance
the audience will never forget.
- Why?
- Because they were elephants.
Please, a little respect for
that joke. It's older than you.
Sorry, Joe.
I see you haven't
been doing so good.
- To tell you the truth, it has been a little...
- You don't have to tell me.
It's the same with us. We haven't
worked since Rosie cut her second teeth.
- Joe, do you live around here?
- I do. I did.
I just moved out less
than a half-hour ago.
- Is the place rented yet?
- I don't think so.
- How much rent did you pay?
- I didn't.
But if you've got $32,
you can move right in.
How long did you live there
without paying any rent?
Six months.
Just what we're looking for.
Something out of the high-rent district.
- It's been good seeing you.
- You must drop in and see us soon.
Yes, thank you.
Wait for me!
- Hadn't you better ask him where it is?
- We ain't got no time.
Joe!
- Where is it?
- 322-and-a-half Maple Street. Over there.
Come on back. It's this way.
Wait for me!
Merry Christmas.
Come here. Here, boy.
Hello.
Pardon this
unseemly protrusion...
but after reading this sign, I
took the liberty of removing it.
- I don't think you'll need it anymore.
- You wanna rent this place?
We might work something out,
if you don't drag lawyers into this.
You'd better speak to my father
about it. He's right next door.
On second thought, I
can handle this myself.
Come in.
Be back in a minute.
Gosh, it's good to be home.
- My name is Amendola.
- My name is Pete Dingle.
Rosalinda.
Joe Mahoney sent us.
That's okay with me, but
don't mention it to my father.
The rent will be $32 a month.
I don't mind electric
bulbs that are unfrosted.
I don't mind beds with
springs that fight back...
or window shades that
curl up like anchovies.
But there's one thing I
can't stand. Leaky faucets.
- Do you mind?
- Not at all.
Perfect.
Mama, you might as
well start unpacking.
This ain't exactly the
bridal suite at the Waldorf.
But who knows? If we give
this place a good cleaning...
- we might find an extra room.
- "Good cleaning" is right.
Look at all those cobwebs.
Don't touch those cobwebs. They're
probably holding the building together.
Now that all the business
has been taken care of...
But you see, my father, unfortunately,
wants his money in advance.
And a lucky man he is, too, your father,
having a son so gifted in the art of music.
I just fool around...
I know. I, too, am a musician.
Modesty compels me to
admit that I play a pretty piano...
and if necessary, I can
even play an ugly one.
Don't forget. Feel free
to drop in at any time.
Thanks very much.
About the rent...
- I think I'm gonna like it here.
- I hope so.
Now, if you don't
mind, I'd like to change.
No, not at all. I mean...
I'll see you later.
- Well, Mama, I did it.
- Look, Pa, he forgot his tuba.
He'll be back. But if he don't, you can
blow on it every night and announce dinner.
You realize what I've done?
No rent in advance, and
a roof over our heads.
There's an awful big
hole in the skylight.
So what? If it snows, we'll be the only
ones in town to have a white Christmas...
inside the house and out.
- Hello, Pete.
- Hi.
I think I got a letter for you.
- No, it's for your old man.
- I'll give it to him.
If I don't see you
tomorrow, merry Christmas.
Same to you.
- Did you clean the place?
- Clean it? I rented it.
Good, you can work if
you make up your mind.
- Who'd you rent it to?
- Their name is Amendola.
Their?
- How many are there?
- Just three.
They're awfully nice people.
That's good for a
change. I'll take the money.
There's a mother and a father...
- and a daughter.
- Okay, give me the $32.
They didn't even ask for any
redecorations or repairing anything.
That saves us a
lot of money, Pa.
Don't tell me you let
them stay without paying.
You're gonna get it.
They're awfully nice people.
A mother, and a
father and a daughter.
You said that before. Look,
son, I want that $32 right now.
If you don't get it, I'll
go and get it myself.
And if I don't get
it, out they go!
But I gave my word of honor
we'd wait a couple of days.
You don't wanna break
your own son's word, do you?
Honor, charity, love thy
neighbor. Everything but money.
Tell me, son, what did money ever
do to you that you hate it so much?
I'll get it.
Oh, hello.
Hello. You forgot
to give me the key.
The key? Yes, the key.
- Here it is.
- Thank you.
Wait a minute.
- You'll stay, won't you?
- If my father...
Who is it, Pete?
Don't go away.
I'll be right back.
- Who was it?
- The postman. It's for you.
National Security Bank.
What do those chiselers want?
What is it?
Just an advertisement.
Katie, come here.
What is it?
That worthless gold mine I
invested in 10 years ago is paying off.
Here's a check for $1,500.
And they say we're gonna get the
same amount each week from now on.
Mercy! It's the day before
Christmas, too. It's money from heaven.
- We should go to church and pray.
- Sure.
But first I'll go down to the
bank and cash the check.
I know that apartment isn't
what you folks have been used to.
- But with a little paint and fixing it up...
- You mean, you'll redecorate it?
I'll speak to my
father about it.
Mother's been having a little
trouble with the stove. It's awfully old.
We'll see what we
can do about that, too.
- Maybe get you another one.
- A new stove!
- Is there somebody asleep in there?
- My father.
My father's a little reluctant
about investing money.
He has to be handled
with kid gloves.
- Say, how about going for a walk?
- Not in these shoes, I wouldn't.
- They pinch my feet.
- Go get some others. I'll wait for you.
It'll be a long wait. I
haven't any others.
What size do you wear?
Dreaming of a size 4. Why?
Stay right where you are.
Not a word of this
to a soul, Katie.
Not anybody, especially
that lazy son of yours.
If he finds out, he'll blow that
blasted tuba the rest of his life.
- Mom, what size shoe do you wear?
- 6, why?
Never mind.
Don't you buy shoes for me for
Christmas. I've got two pairs already.
Isn't that nice? Not a nickel in his
pocket, and he wants to buy me shoes.
Just for that, Frank, I want you
to buy a nice necktie for him...
and put it under the Christmas tree.
He likes those hand-painted ones.
I saw some perfectly
lovely ones for only $5.
$5, eh?
I'll get some paint out of
the attic and paint one myself.
They called us the Amendola
Trio, the Human Pyramid.
Papa balanced Mama
on his shoulders...
and then I stood on top of
Mama, all done up like a little angel.
Sounds exciting.
Papa juggled, Mama
sang, and I played the harp.
Used to go over big.
Only I started growing,
Mama got heavier...
and one day,
Papa's legs gave out.
You mean he dropped you?
Four times in one week. The
fourth time, Mama broke her leg.
You gotta hand
it to Papa, though.
He never broke a plate.
He's a great juggler.
Look, there's my father,
coming out of the bank.
- Wonder what he was doing in the bank.
- I've never been in a bank.
Just to think of all that
money in one place.
A week ago, this tree was $7.
Yesterday, $4. Now, what are my bids?
- 40 cents.
- Make it $1.
One dollar.
I wish we were
gonna have a tree.
Of course, with
the moving and all...
We've talked enough about
me. Tell me, where do you work?
I don't. That is, I write music.
- Does it pay?
- No.
Then you don't work.
- I don't have a job.
- Can't you find one?
- I've never looked for one.
- What about money?
I don't need money.
Suppose you were walking with a
girl, and she wanted a malted milk.
What would you do?
Well, that would be
pretty embarrassing.
I'm sorry I said that, Pete.
Come on, let's go home.
Folks, just two more left.
What am I bid for this one?
- 40 cents.
- $1.50.
$1.50. Do I hear $2?
$1.50, once, twice. Sold
to this gentleman for $1.50!
Now for the last tree. It's your last
chance. What're my bids for this one?
- 40 cents.
- 75 cents.
Do I hear $1? Will
someone make it $1?
- 75 cents, once, twice...
- $1.
$1, I've got. Once, twice,
sold to this gentleman for $1.
Here you are, buddy.
Say, mister, would it be all
right if I pay you 40 cents now...
and the balance later?
Sure! Just take the elevator to the
18th floor. That's our credit department.
This is a cash sale, buddy. Do
you want the tree or don't you?
Hey, wait!
Look, you can have the
tree. Give me the 40 cents.
Thanks!
I'll pay you the rest
as soon as I can.
I'll give you a week. If
you don't pay by then...
I'll find out where you
live and take the tree back.
...11, 12...
13, 14, 15.
- Why didn't you leave it at the bank?
- At the bank?
Katie, you're not serious.
After all that happened to
our little savings in 1929?
No, sirree, they're never gonna
get any of my money again.
I'm going to hide it
right in this house.
You better run over to the church
and say that little prayer now.
You're sending me away...
because you want to keep the
hiding place a secret from me.
No, it isn't you,
Katie. It's Pete.
You're too soft-hearted
with that boy.
- I'm afraid that...
- What's the use of money if you hide it?
Money's for buying things...
to enjoy life, to
have some pleasure.
That's a lot of hooey.
Money's for security...
not to worry about the
future, to enjoy sleep.
All right, Frank, I'm going.
I don't care if you stick
that money up the chimney...
and let it smoke till it
smells like a ham butt.
How long is it going to be?
Moving from one
place to another.
Always moving...
never having a
place to call our home.
Believe me, Lord,
we've tried so hard.
We've tried
everything. Everything.
But it's so difficult to find
a job for a human pyramid.
You're our only hope.
So it's up to you.
Please.
Tomorrow is Christmas.
We haven't even got a tree.
No money to buy
some little gifts.
Not even a pair of
shoes for Rosalinda.
She must have those shoes, Lord.
She needs them real bad.
Thank you!
Tell me, Rosalinda...
- do you still play the harp?
- Sure, why?
I think I'll compose something
just for the harp and tuba.
And I'm gonna call it The Melody
Of Two Orphaned Instruments.
That's a cute title.
- You think they'll go together?
- I don't know.
But I'm hoping.
Papa! Wait!
But I don't understand.
A tree! Presents!
And look at it, Papa, a turkey!
And cranberry sauce, plum
pudding, candy, and nuts.
And, look, brand-new shoes.
But how? I don't understand.
You couldn't have won
it on a quiz program.
- We haven't got any phone.
- No, Papa, I didn't win anything.
Mama! Your wedding
ring! You didn't hock your...
- No, I didn't hock anything. All I did...
- I know.
You wired that drummer in
Boston who had a crush on you.
That sheik with the patent
leather shoes and tuxedo.
I remember what he said when
we announced our engagement.
"If ever you needed anything- ♪
Papa, that was 22 years ago.
I don't care if it
was 100 years ago!
I never trusted a
guy with a tuxedo...
especially a rented one.
Let Mama explain, Papa.
No, the money
didn't come from him.
It came from...
Here, Papa, you'd
better sit down.
- Better loosen your collar, Papa.
- Rosalinda, bring Papa a glass of water.
Papa, you love me, don't you?
- Of course I love you.
- And you trust me?
You'd believe me if I told
you something, wouldn't you?
Even if nobody else in the
world would believe me...
you would believe me,
wouldn't you, Papa?
Sure, I would, Mama.
I was sitting right
here in this chair...
and I was praying.
This money...
$1,500..
Come floating right down
through the hole in the skylight.
$1.500?
- From heaven?
- You do believe me, don't you, Papa?
If you said it, I
gotta believe you.
Merry Christmas, Papa.
You see, Rosie? I told you
old Saint Nick wouldn't forget us.
All we needed was an address.
Frank, this perfume
is lovely. "Dangerous."
Such a big bottle. It must
have cost at least $10.
It's not that dangerous.
This is a terrific tie,
Dad. Thanks again.
Did you see the watermelons,
Mama? They're hand-painted.
Now, who's that?
Merry Christmas, young
man. May we come in?
Why, of course.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you.
Why, Mr. Amendola, we
have the exact same ties on.
It could be a lot worse if we were
girls wearing the same dresses.
Mom, Dad, this is
Mr. and Mrs. Amendola...
- and their daughter, Rosalinda.
- How do you do?
We're your new tenants, and the
Yuletide season being upon us...
we thought we'd drop
in and pay you a visit.
- To pay what?
- A visit, Frank.
Make yourselves comfortable.
- Do sit down.
- Thanks.
- I'm glad you brought your harp.
- Can we put it right over here?
That's a nice tree you
got there, Mr. Dingle.
Where did you
get it? Molineri's?
Maybe we ought to go down there next
week and make our payments together.
Payments? Speaking
of payments...
just what do you
do for a living?
Doesn't the name of Amendola
suggest nothing to you?
You surely must have
seen us perform some place.
Florida in the racing season,
Lake Placid in the winter season...
or perhaps Africa in
the malaria season.
Yes, sir, someday you'll be able to
say the Amendolas were your tenants.
If I don't get my rent money,
I'll be able to say that tomorrow.
I'm glad you brought
that up, Mr. Dingle.
Now, if you'll just hang
your sock on the mantle...
I'll drop in three months' rent.
Keep the $4 change.
Three months' rent in advance.
Mr. Amendola, we're so glad
you folks dropped in on us.
Katie, get
Mr. Amendola a chair...
and some coffee and cake.
Where's the Christmas spirit?
That's right, where is
the Christmas spirit?
I love the excitement
of Christmas.
I'll never forget one Christmas
Eve when I was a kid.
I hung my stocking up on
the mantle and went to bed.
When I woke up the next morning,
what do you think I found in the stocking?
My father's foot!
Soft.
Wait a minute!
Another outburst
like that, Mr. Dingle...
and I'll hide your
electric trains.
Soft.
Soft!
How do you like that? There's a
guy going in business for himself.
Wait a minute. All together!
This is wonderful.
Mr. Dingle, this is gonna develop
into a long and beautiful friendship...
even closer than
Damon and Phythenias.
You'll notice Rosalinda
brought her harp along.
She didn't bring it to
slice hard-boiled eggs.
All right, Rosalinda.
- Here you are, Rosalinda.
- Thank you.
I finished The Melody for
Two Orphaned Instruments.
- Wanna try it?
- Sure. Set the music right over here, Pete.
- Here you are.
- Thanks.
- Ready?
- Yes.
I don't want my
wife to hear this.
The stage has
always fascinated me.
Don't you think I've got
a very fine singing voice?
Why, the bathtubs of the world
are full of singers, Mr. Dingle.
But did you ever hear of anyone
doing a backflip in the bathtub? No.
And you know the reason why?
Because only a few
of us are acrobats.
Acrobats. I'd just love
to learn a few tricks.
I'm always so dull when
company comes. I can't do a thing.
Can you teach me a few things?
I'd be glad to teach you.
You got anything around here that
we could rig up like a teeterboard?
- A seesaw?
- Yeah.
I think so. Let me see, now.
- How about a table leaf?
- You got one? Go get it.
Great, now get
me a glass of water.
Thanks.
This is so simple, I taught it to
Rosalinda when she was only 3 years old.
Now you get up on that chair.
I'll stand down at this end, place
the glass of water on my head...
and when I say go, you
jump down on that end.
I will then do a back somersault,
light a cigarette in midair...
and land in that chair without
spilling one drop of water.
- Ready?
- Ready.
Go.
Termites.
That's so pretty, Pete.
And he wrote it himself.
How well he plays the tuba!
- It's lovely, Pete.
- So are you.
Gosh, Rosalinda,
your hair, your dress...
- Gosh, you're beautiful.
- Thank you, Pete.
- May I have this, Pete?
- Sure.
I wrote it for you.
Look, somebody's coming
to see us, in a beautiful car.
Rosalinda, go down and see who it
is. It might be somebody important.
- Yes?
- Hello. Is Joe Mahoney home?
- He's moved away.
- He has?
- You know where he went?
- I'm afraid I don't.
That's great. What do I do with
this Christmas present I brought him?
Here, it's yours.
- Go ahead.
- I really don't...
It's just fruit and things.
- You live here?
- Yes.
- Alone?
- With my parents.
That's nice.
- Anything I can do for you?
- My name is Phil Davis.
- I'm a friend of Joe Mahoney's...
- Phil Davis, the agent?
- Yes, that's me.
- Believe me, this is a pleasure.
My name is Amendola. You've heard
of the Amendola Trio, haven't you?
You know, the Human
Pyramid? Come in.
Now, don't pay any attention
to this apartment, Mr. Davis.
We just moved in yesterday.
Not much of a place...
but for certain reasons
it fascinates me.
Mr. Davis, take a
look at this poster.
You're gazing at one of the
greatest vaudeville acts of its time.
And the only reason
we disbanded...
was because of my little
daughter's rapid maturity.
- Yes, I can see what you mean.
- Mr. Davis, I was just thinking...
I can work alone. Why, I can
out-juggle anyone in the business.
You know something? I can
juggle 25 plates with one hand.
And with the other hand,
I pick up the broken ones.
Just a little joke
I use in the act.
Now if you give me
your undivided attention...
Say, that's good. That's
great. How did you do it?
How did you do it?
What? That's a trade secret.
- Do it again.
- Yes, do it again, Papa.
Rosalinda, you know the great
Amendola never repeats twice.
That's very clever. I'll try
and book you, Mr. Amendola.
Sure.
- How about you?
- About me?
I'm sorry to butt in,
but the coffee's ready.
A girl with your looks and
figure should be in the limelight.
And I'm just the man
that can put you there.
Said he as he twirled his black
mustache and eyed the proud beauty.
- Who's he?
- Please.
You were saying, Mr. Davis?
A girl like you should
have a decent place to live.
Not a dump like this.
What's good enough
for my parents...
Is hardly good enough
for a raving beauty like you.
- And Mr. Davis here is just...
- Please.
The coffee's ready. It's
getting cold, and so is the cake.
I'm sorry, but Mr. Davis is a
very important Broadway agent.
- Broadway chiseler.
- I beg your pardon. What was that?
I know the type.
Promises young girls expensive
clothes, diamonds, furs.
- Anything to make an impression.
- He didn't say that. You did.
He was going to.
What right has he got to call me a
chiseler? He doesn't even know me.
I think he's jealous.
Maybe he's got a case.
Say, it's Christmas,
and I'm all alone.
How about me taking you
out to a Chinese dinner tonight?
I'm sorry, but I was...
I'd love to.
Father, may I go
out with Mr. Davis?
- You better ask your mother.
- Thanks a lot.
I threw five nuts up,
and only four came down.
This defies the laws of gravity.
It's midnight. She
isn't home yet.
Mama, stop worrying.
Nothing can happen to her.
She's not alone.
She's with a man.
Another miracle
happened this afternoon.
- A miracle?
- I tried to juggle a few walnuts.
- One didn't come down. It just disappeared.
- Mercy me.
This is a strange house. Money
comes down and walnuts go up.
But I guess that's better than money
going up and walnuts coming down.
I don't know what to make of it.
Katie, Katie!
What is it, Frank?
I've been thinking about
that Amendola family.
Why should people who can
afford three months' rent in advance...
wanna live in a dump like that?
Frank, last night you couldn't sleep
because they didn't pay their rent.
Tonight you can't
sleep because they did.
For goodness' sake, stop
worrying and go to sleep.
Why don't you check out of
this town? Come to New York.
- Things can happen to you there, Rosie.
- Let's not start that again, Phil.
I'm crazy about you,
Rosie. I'll do anything for you.
Do you know any
music publishers, Phil?
Sure, dozens of them. Why?
I wrote some music. I think it's
beautiful. If you could take it...
I didn't know you
were a composer.
"Melody for Two Orphaned
Instruments by Peter Dingle."
Who's Peter Dingle?
You see, I put a
man's name on it...
because I knew no one would even
look at it if they knew a girl wrote it.
I'll see what I can do. If it's any
good, I'll try and get it published.
- Thanks a lot, Phil. Good night.
- Wait a minute.
See you tomorrow.
- I'm sorry to wake you up, Mr. Haggerty.
- What's the matter, Pete? Somebody sick?
Yeah, me. I want that job.
Do you want to start right now, or
can you wait till tomorrow morning?
I'm sorry, I was afraid
somebody else might get it.
You see, Mr. Haggerty,
I need money.
Hey, Pete.
Yeah?
Bend closer, laddie boy.
This is for your ears alone.
I got a sure thing in the
sixth at California today.
Cut me in on 40 percent,
and I'll give it to you.
This one can't lose.
It'll win in a walk.
And while our horse is walking,
the others will be running.
If you have another hot tip,
Mulligan, leave it under the plate.
- Yes, sir?
- What's your best cigar?
- Good ones are a quarter apiece.
- Quarter apiece?
How much does a whole one cost?
- It's just a little joke.
- As little as I've heard.
Pete.
- Hello.
- Hi.
What will it be?
- I didn't know you worked here, Pete.
- That's strange. It was in the papers.
But remember, once you told
me you were opposed to work.
Sure.
I even remember I couldn't buy a
certain girl a cool drink in a drugstore.
Now, not only can I buy it,
but serve it, too. What will it be?
You took this job
on account of me.
The girl I'm referring to
only wanted a malted milk.
Can we go now?
- It's you. Let's go, honey.
- I'd like a malted milk, Phil.
- Not in this dump, please.
- Goodbye.
So long.
Pete, you're missing a great bid.
That filly's sure to wind up in the money.
Yeah, that's what I'm afraid of.
How's that for a
bargain? Only $49.50.
But, Papa, what do we
want with a polar bear rug?
This isn't an ordinary
polar bear. Just watch.
All you got to do is
twist the tooth and...
Music! It's also a radio.
The other tooth
is for shortwave.
- But we don't need it.
- Sure we do.
It lends an air of
quality to the place.
Mama, what's a real
home without a polar bear?
But we must stop buying things.
That $500 you have
left has got to last.
I'm glad you brought that up.
You know that Mr. Byfield, who we
bought these few pieces of furniture off?
I stopped by there today to look at
that little piano we were talking about.
And you know something?
- He isn't doing so well.
- Papa, I hope you didn't...
It's not his fault
that business is bad.
Naturally, with the banks
leaning on the place...
- and no one to...
- Our last $500.
Papa, all our lives,
you've been doing this.
Whenever we get a little ahead,
you meet someone who's in trouble...
and you just melt like
chocolate in a baby's hand.
I couldn't help
it. He needed it.
But, Mama, we got nothing to worry about.
We still got that $100 I gave you yesterday.
No, I mailed that money away for
the unpaid bills we left in Chicago.
That puts us right back
where we were a week ago.
That's right. All you gotta do
is do what you did a week ago.
Pray.
Lam praying every
hour of the day.
But if it's more money
you want me to pray for...
Why not, Mother?
It's worth a try.
I just wouldn't have
the nerve to ask again.
Besides, it's selfish.
But Papa just told us he
helped somebody with it.
That wasn't selfish.
And besides, all you gotta do is ask,
and let heaven make up its own mind.
- Even if I could remember the prayer...
- You must remember, Mother.
- The same thing you said before.
- I don't know.
All I recall saying is that
Rosalinda needs shoes.
But now she doesn't need
shoes. She has four pairs already.
But, Mama, when you
say she needs shoes...
that doesn't mean
she really needs them.
It's like stagehands in the
theater playing dice. A guy says:
"Baby needs a
new pair of shoes."
That doesn't mean she needs them.
It's just a disfigurement of speech.
- All right, bring me the little old rocker.
- I'll get it.
I was sitting in it
when it happened.
Say it, Mama.
Please, help us. Rosalinda needs
shoes. She needs them real bad.
It's no use, Mama. The
prayer won't be answered.
Maybe it has been answered,
and the answer is no.
We're grateful, anyhow.
I guess I'd better take
this rug back to the shop.
Please forgive
me for telling a lie.
Rosalinda doesn't need shoes.
Come back! It's coming down!
It happened exactly a week
ago at about the same time.
- Exactly $1,500 again.
- Bless me!
All you gotta do is sit in that old
rocker every Thursday at 3:30 and say:
"Rosalinda needs
shoes," and collect $1,500.
It's funny how
simple life can be.
It's coming down.
- Hello, Petrushka.
- Here's your pies and cake, Mr. Amendola.
- Thanks.
- And here's a check.
Your share of our
profits for this month.
You cast your dough upon
the waters, it circulates...
and it comes back
strawberry shortcake.
- Thanks, partner.
- Thank you, Mr. Amendola.
- Who was it, Papa?
- Petrushka, our baker.
Oh, mama.
Look.
This is our share
of the month's profit.
How much did we decide to contribute
to buy shoes for European children?
$600.Why?
Deposit this, and we
can make it $1,000.
That's fine.
It's all over town. This Amendola
character gave $1,025 for kids' shoes.
He lives in a stable
and sleeps on straw.
He doesn't work. It don't add
up. Where does he get the money?
He gave $2,500 for
European children.
- What line of business is he in?
- Nobody knows.
Read all about it! Local man
gives thousands to charity!
Read all about it!
When they moved in, they
didn't have a nickel to their name.
Two months later, he buys a
shipload of shoes for foreign kids.
Now, how do you figure that?
I'd like a Super-Duper
Triple-Decker Banana Delight.
Coming UP-
You know what I think?
He's printing his own money, right
there in that shack of yours, Mr. Dingle.
I hate gossip. But I just
heard from a friend of mine...
whose wife told him,
and she swears it's true...
that Amendola is a
big gangster in hiding.
And if I was you, Mr. Dingle,
I'd notify the police right away.
Notify the FBI. I
saw it in a movie.
Someone should write
them an anonymous letter.
Sure, write anonymous letters.
Report him to the police. Put him in jail.
The guy has to be punished
because he has a big heart.
Pipe down, Pete. I told you
never to argue with the customers.
Sorry.
I think it's all a lot of hooey.
You know what I heard?
A man comes to see the pretty
Amendola girl every day in a big car.
- We can't hear you.
- Louder.
A man comes to see their
daughter every day in a big car.
True. He's a Broadway
agent. What about him?
- Like a little strawberry?
- Sure.
He's the individual that floods Amendola
with money, on account of that girl.
- Some whipped cream?
- Love that.
That's what I say about actors.
People like the Amendolas can
contaminate a whole community.
Just like one rotten
apple in a barrel.
Pete!
Oh, my goodness!
I forgot the cherry.
- What will it be?
- Bourbon and water.
- Hi, Pete.
- Hi.
Say, I had dinner
at the drugstore...
and I heard you pushed a chocolate sundae
into a perfectly good customer's kisser.
- Is it true?
- No, it was a Banana Delight.
You're hurt, Pete.
Who hurt you, boy?
Nobody. I just
counted my money...
and I discovered I was 16
cents short of my first million.
That makes me sad.
Listen, Pete, if you're
open to a proposition...
I know how to make
some real dough.
Get this. A friend of mine...
Look, Eddie, why don't you make
like a ballerina and dance away?
Here, stick this in the jukebox
and play something loud.
This friend of mine is
drilling for oil in California.
He's down 9,000 feet.
Got 500 more to go.
So now it's oil stocks. Don't
you ever give up, Mulligan?
But, Pete, for only $2,000, you can
grab yourself 20 percent interest...
and become a
millionaire in no time.
Are you out of your mind?
Where would I get $2,000?
How about asking your old man?
Don't be ridiculous. My
father gets a small pension.
- He's happy if he can make ends meet.
- That's what you think, Junior.
My brother-in-law, who happens
to be a policeman at the bank...
says that old man of yours has been
cashing pretty large checks for weeks now.
Wait a minute. I did see him
coming out of the bank once.
- He gets a letter from them every week.
- You see?
All you have to do is
ask him to back you.
What father could
refuse such a proposition?
Tell me, Mulligan, is
this really on the level?
Tell you what I'll do.
I'll introduce you to my friend.
He'll show you the papers.
And besides, he'll give
you all the security you want.
I'll see you tomorrow.
There must be a screw loose in your
head. Who's got $2,000? What $2,000?
I know you have it. You've been
seen in the bank cashing large checks.
That's a lie. Now get out. I
don't want to hear any more.
I'll pay you back. I'll
repay you 10 times over.
But I haven't
got it, I tell you!
Pa, you must give it
to me. You simply must.
Get out, you crazy fool. Get out before I
break that blasted tuba over your head.
Get out!
- Goodbye.
- I'll walk you there.
No, that's all right.
- Sure you can get in all right?
- Sure.
Good night.
Oh, Pete.
Hello, Rosalinda.
It's a beautiful
night, isn't it?
- Mind if I join you?
- No.
Not at all.
I wanna talk to you.
What is it, Pete?
That is, I have no
right to say this, but...
Say it anyhow, Pete. It might
be something I'd like to hear.
It's the money your father's spending.
They think it's coming from Davis.
- From Phil?
- Yeah.
They say he's in love with you.
You don't believe
that, do you, Pete?
I can see how anyone might
get a wrong impression...
about Phil and me, I mean.
But there isn't anything
between us, Pete.
I can't explain about the money,
because there isn't any explanation, but...
There's no need for one...
not about Davis, or the money...
or anything.
Then, what is it, Pete?
Why are we sitting here like
this, when all you have to say is...
What's the use, Rosalinda?
All right, suppose I
am in love with you.
That's not enough.
$2,000, plus more luck
than I dare hope for...
and we might be able
to do something about it.
A marriage license
only costs $2.
Yeah, but how could we live?
- We could manage.
- How?
By putting windows in my tuba
and converting it into a Quonset hut?
My mother and father didn't have
a penny when they were married.
And Papa says that was the
happiest time in their whole lives.
Very true.
That's great. But I
can't even juggle.
We'll have to take that up
the first thing in the morning.
But why must we have $2,000?
It's an oil deal, and
it might come in.
Then again, it might
not. But if it did...
What's the use trying to
dream my way out of it?
Pete, maybe Papa
can lend you the money.
- Maybe.
- But $2,000?
- You can ask him.
- I'm sorry, Rosalinda.
I'm superstitious about borrowing
money that comes from heaven.
Oh, Pete.
Mr. Amendola.
I couldn't help overhearing you
and Rosalinda talking out here.
It's not that I was eavesdrooping,
or that I meant to listen.
I just had to get up and
fill the cold water bottle.
You see, my feet
get very hot at night.
I hope we didn't disturb you.
What disturbs me is this idea you
got about Rosalinda and this guy Davis.
Believe me,
there's nothing to it.
Why, if you'd look with your
heart instead of your eyes...
you could see where
her best intentions are.
Look, Mr. Amendola, it
isn't Rosalinda. It's me.
Sure it's you. I heard what
you says about being broke.
And if you ask me, I think your
get-up-and-go has got up and went.
What you need is confidence.
And listen. About that
$2,000, I'd be very glad to...
I couldn't take your
money, Mr. Amendola.
Of course, the oil
might come in...
but right now, it's just a hole
in the ground in California.
So what? Uncle Sam put
money in a hole in the ground...
and it turned out
to be Fort Knox.
And I can take a risk, too.
But let's talk about
it in the morning.
- Mama, where's Rosalinda?
- Went for a walk with the boy next door.
You know, Papa, I think
that's getting serious.
Serious? They might get
married and have a couple of kids.
- But that's as far as it would go.
- Oh, Papa.
Mama, remember this?
Vaguely-
Some boy who was courting me
used to sing it to me 22 years ago.
Who was that, now?
Was it the wealthy cattleman from
Montana, or that drummer from Boston?
Mama, that was me.
Of course it was, Papa. And I've been
singing myself to sleep with it ever since.
Sing it, Papa.
I remember.
- Yes, gentlemen?
- We're not together.
I'm Lieutenant Saunders, Police. I'm
looking for a man named Louis Amendola.
That's me.
I'm Inspector Tainey,
Bureau of Internal Revenue.
- May I come in?
- Sure.
- What did you do, Papa?
- I don't know.
Unless I've been burning
the incinerator after-hours.
Gentlemen, this is my wife.
Now all we need is the FBI.
Pardon me.
Callahan, FBI. Are
you Mr. Amendola?
- Yes, sir. Won't you come in?
- Thanks.
Me and my big, fat mouth.
Mr. Amendola, I'd like to
ask you a few questions...
Do you mind? I was here first.
Mr. Amendola, the Department
of Internal Revenue...
would like some information
regarding your source of income.
- Income?
- A report...
Please. May I?
We have a report showing you've
been spending large sums of money...
the source of which is not indicated
in your previous income-tax reports.
We're a little curious, Mr. Amendola, to
know where the money is coming from.
We saved a lot when we
were the Human Pyramid.
And I took that money
and I invested it wisely.
I'll have you know that I've majored
in Economics at Cranfus College.
Cranfus? Never
heard of that college.
That's like saying you
never heard of Joe Tupis.
- Who's he?
- He's the President of Cranfus!
Mr. Amendola, we're not
interested in your education.
We just want to know where
you're getting the money.
All right, gentlemen.
I'll tell you the truth.
I'm the long lost son of
a very wealthy typhoon.
When I was only two days old, a nurse
turned her back while changing me...
and I was stolen from the cradle
by a band of starving gypsies.
A few months ago, the king of the gypsies
came and told me who my father was.
I see you don't believe me.
All right, I'll tell
you the truth.
I was down at the beach,
digging with my pail and shovel...
when suddenly my shovel struck
the top of an ironbound chest.
- Pirates' treasure?
- That's right.
That does it. Look here, Amendola,
you've been reported for everything...
from swiping tires off baby
carriages to operating your own mint.
- What's your racket?
- Leave him alone.
Why can't we tell them the
truth, darling? It's so simple.
- All right, lady, what is the truth?
- Where does the money come from?
From heaven.
That explains everything.
But it's the truth. It comes
straight from heaven.
- $1,500 every week.
- On the dot.
I like the one about
the pirates' chest better.
Come on, Amendola, let's go
and tell it to the boys at the station.
But I can prove it. I
can prove every word...
- Now, how can you prove it?
- It's easy.
I put this old rocking chair
in the middle of the room...
sit down there, and
say a little prayer.
And when I say,
"Rosalinda needs shoes..."
The money comes down like rain.
- All right, Mrs. Amendola, show us.
- Pull up the chair and say the prayer.
Wait a minute. She
can't do it today.
The miracle happens on
Thursday between 3:00 and 3:30.
- We'll be here Thursday at 3:00.
- Thursday at 3:00.
I should doubt my veracity.
Look.
And I hear they're both
doing tremendous business.
They are? All right,
come on, let's go.
Look.
How's business, Mr. Molinari?
Couldn't be better. More
orders than we can take care of.
Come on, Katie, let's go.
Clever man, that Amendola.
Soon he'll own the whole town.
You could've done the same, if you'd
invested your money instead of hiding it.
Marx and Amendola Garage.
- Look at that.
- No, I won't look!
And don't stop every
second. I'm getting tired of this.
You know what I'm gonna do? Lam
gonna raise Amendola's rent again.
As of today! Come on.
Due to the increased cost of living,
I must raise the rent of this place.
Again?
This is the eighth time you've
raised the rent since we moved in.
You're forcing me to join
Landlords Anonymous.
You can move out if you want to.
Let's not be too
hasty, Mr. Dingle.
You might be right. Maybe
the cost of living has increased.
I wouldn't know, I haven't
done today's shopping yet.
How much more do you want?
- $30.
- $30? $125 a month? Why, it's robbery!
If you think that, you can
start packing right now.
He didn't mean that,
Mr. Dingle. Did you, Papa?
Of course not.
I apologize, Mr. Dingle.
Why, for only $125 a month,
where else could you find a place...
where the sunshine comes
streaming through the keyhole all day?
You're right. You can't
take advantage of me...
- like those bankrupt shop owners.
- Now, look here.
I only helped them out
because no one else would.
And besides, I'm not making
money on all those investments.
For instance, your
son's oil venture.
I'll surely lose the
$2,000 I invested in that.
You deserve to. He
couldn't take me for a sucker.
- I wouldn't give him a nickel.
- If you did...
you'd probably shortchange
him, you tight old buzzard.
That's done it. Another word out of
you, and I'll punch you in the nose!
- Why, I'll...
- Papa! Mr. Dingle!
Why, you two should be friends,
if only for our children's sake.
They love one another.
Who knows? They might
get married someday.
No son of mine will ever marry a
girl with your daughter's reputation.
Get out!
Papa, the chair.
- It's broken.
- Get me some nails and glue.
I'll fix it. Hurry! It's
almost time to pray.
"We are sorry to
inform you that..."
Katie!
Yes, Frank?
Our gold mine is exhausted.
There'll be no more checks.
- Let's get going. It's almost 3:30.
- Okay.
All right, Mama.
Say it.
Rosalinda needs shoes.
- Look...
- Gentlemen, a little patience.
$1, 500 is a lot of money.
Sometimes we gotta ask twice.
Try it again, Mama.
Rosalinda needs shoes.
Once again.
I guess you're right, Mama.
It seems the miracle is over.
I threw away $1,500 a
week when I threw this chair.
It's not the chair.
It's that we have no
excuse to ask for any more.
You're right. But we're
doing all right, now.
There's a lot of poor
people praying in this world.
Now ifs their tum for miracles.
I'm moving out of here the
first thing tomorrow morning.
Now even my cigarettes
don't come down.
I'm afraid you won't
have to wait till then.
You'll have to move
now, down to the station.
Not so fast, Lieutenant. This is
a tax matter. He goes with me.
Wait a minute, you two. I don't
know what kind of a matter this is...
but he's going with
me for questioning.
- Question him at the station.
- I don't want to.
I want to question
him at my field office.
I don't care where you question
him. He's going with me now.
Over my broken
and splintered body.
I have no objection to taking him
over your broken and splintered body.
Gentlemen, let's have
cooperation. Let him go with me.
Good night, Pete.
Good night, Rosalinda.
Mama, Papa, what's the matter?
These people don't understand
where we're getting our money from.
So I'm going downtown and
explaining it. You stay here with Mother.
Is there anything I can do?
Pardon us a moment, will you?
Look, I don't know how
long I'm gonna be gone.
Kinda keep an eye on
things till I get back, will you?
Sure. But there's
trouble. Is it serious?
There's nothing to it.
With time off for good
behavior, I may only get life.
- All right, gentlemen, whose car do I go in?
- Mine.
I smell smoke.
So do I.
But, Dad, Mr. Amendola's in serious
trouble. Maybe the $2,000 would help him.
- You've got to give it to him.
- I think you should.
- He helped Pete.
- Helped him how?
To make an idiot out of
himself by giving him $2,000".
For that crook
Mulligan. I won't do it!
I won't give Amendola one penny.
Let him fry in his own
fat. He belongs in jail.
But, Dad, this is important.
Frank, you're a hard-hearted,
money-hoarding...
I'm going upstairs, where I don't
have to listen to either one of you.
Help! I'm choking!
Don't worry, Dad.
Come on, Dad.
- I gotta get my money!
- Forget your money.
It's in a hole behind the bed.
Mom, I've got him.
The money! I want
to get the money!
Let me go!
The polar bear rug with the radio!
I'll miss The Jimmy Durante Show.
Here it is, Papa!
- Thousands of dollars. It's all gone.
- Heaven knows you deserve it.
Are we insured, Pa?
Heck, no. Those chiselers
don't get any of my money, no sir.
Good heavens, I'm not insured!
You have a very smart father. He
trusts nobody but the hole behind the bed.
Pete, I'm so glad
you're all right.
Thousands of dollars burning right
now. Brand-new, crisp $100 bills.
He put them in a
hole behind his bed.
Every Thursday,
$1,500. Now it's all gone.
"Rosalinda needs shoes"?
Pull yourself
together, Mr. Dingle.
HI rebuild the house.
It'll be better than new.
- You will?
- I don't know what to say.
It's perfectly all
right, Mrs. Dingle.
Why, anything to
help a good neighbor.
The way I see it, now this is
very definitely only a tax matter.
- This makes things much simpler.
- What do you mean?
Who owes the tax?
Amendola, or this other guy?
Naturally, the...
I guess Amendola. I don't
know. They both had incomes.
- Maybe they both owe us.
- How? It was this other fellow's income.
Sure. Amendola was only
innocently using the other guy's money.
It was like a gift.
In that case, this man not only owes income
tax, he'll have to pay us gift tax, too.
As far as I'm concerned, the
local law is no longer interested.
Looks like it's out of
my jurisdiction, too.
It's too involved for me. I'm
gonna forget all about till March 15.
- What did you find?
- Nothing but a dead squirrel.
He isn't dead. He's just overcome by
smoke. All he needs is a little fresh air.
Wonder what he was
doing in the house.
That's the place for
a little squirrel to be.
- Thanks for the lift.
- Okay.
Rupert.
My good old Rupert.
You haven't changed a bit.
You smell a little smoky,
though. Now, tell me, how was it?
How did the other squirrels
treat you? Were they good?
I've got good news for you.
I got a job with a circus, and
we start in two weeks in Hoboken.
Me and two seals.
- Greetings, Mr. and Mrs. Dingle.
- Mr. Amendola.
- For your new home, Mrs. Dingle.
- Thank you.
- Go ahead, Papa.
- Make your speech.
Mr. Dingle...
like a caterpillar
has its cocoon...
like a bird has its nest...
like the worm has its...
apple, believe me...
it's a pleasure to present you
with the key to your new home.
Mr. Amendola...
you're the finest, the
noblest, the most generous...
I wouldn't say that, Mr. Dingle.
But I'm glad he did.
I'm overwhelmed. I
can't find words enough...
Words. What are words?
If it'll make you any happier, I'll
even carry you across the threshold.
Thank you, Mr. Amendola.
Our old home, Frank.
- And it's nicer than before.
- I'm glad you like it.
My little wife crocheted the doilies, but
I'll have to take credit for the curtains.
I would have done a much better
job, only my pinking shears were dull.
- Pete.
- Mulligan.
- Why, you dirty, double-crossing...
- No, wait a minute.
Let me go.
We're rich, Pete! The
oil is coming like a geyser.
What? The well came in?
Rosie, come down here, quick!
Phil.
You don't mean it, Phil?
Hey, look here, Davis!
Pete, listen. It's your
music. Phil just told me.
- What is it?
- Be quiet and listen to the radio.
...The Melody for Two Orphaned
Instruments by Peter Dingle.
You did this, Rosalinda.
You see what! Mean
about taking a risk?
Speaking of risks, Pete, when
are you gonna ask me to marry you?
Right now.
They're gonna get married.
Rosalinda.
Pete!
- Amendola, my friend.
- Dingle, old pal.